Inggit is married?
Yes, he’s the one with Rahayu.
He's Inggit's husband.
Why do you want to do this?
If you have a reason to refuse
this arranged marriage,...
I have a reason to accept it.
I made you breakfast.
Tempeh bacem and bacem tofu.
You still want to get an A, don't you?
I was going to be angry with you,
you know.
(Previously)
If something's wrong, you can tell me.
What's wrong?
It's about Tristan.
I'm sorry, Arya.
I think he's old enough
to take care of himself.
If I can give you my suggestion,...
maybe it's best
that you focus on your mom.
She needs you a lot more right now.
Okay? That's my suggestion.
Hello?
Yes, good afternoon.
Listen.
Regarding the learning materials,...
right now,
I have family matters to take care of.
It might be a little late.
I'll try to be back on schedule
next week. It should be fine.
I'm really sorry. Sorry.
Yes, I'll try. Yes. Okay. Thank you.
Mom, you're not resting?
Sit, Arya. I want to talk to you.
Inggit.
-Inggit.
-Yes, Mom?
Come here, Inggit.
I think it's time for the two of you
to go back to Jakarta.
No way, Mom. How can we leave you?
You've stayed with me long enough here.
I'm stronger now.
Mom.
I honestly don't mind staying here
with you for a little longer.
The same with Inggit.
I'm sure that you need Inggit
to be close to you.
Arya.
I know that you really care about me.
But I think it's time
that we all get back to our own lives.
I'm sure that Inggit's dad
agrees with me.
Okay? Go on home.
I'm okay.
♪You are supposed to lecture me♪
♪But then you stopped and looked at me♪
♪I still can't believe
How far you could see♪
♪All of the care that you displayed♪
♪All of the charming things
That you said♪
♪Somehow made me think
That we are meant to be♪
♪You make me feel every love in me♪
♪You let me heal from my history♪
♪Now you have found your way
Into my heart to stay♪
♪Your passion in me♪
♪Has turned out to be♪
♪The reason
That I've been made complete♪
=My Lecturer My Husband=
Tamarind Soup
was your dad's favorite food.
Once he made me promise...
that I’d only cook with a happy heart.
So that our food would be delicious.
Yes, Dad really hate
when he sees us sad or down.
I agree with him, Mom.
It's very important to remember
something happy about someone.
Especially if it's about cooking.
Hopefully I can stay true to his words.
If I'm going to cook,
I have to be happy.
Well, you're his favorite son-in-law.
Of course he is. He’s the only one.
Drink some water.
You haven't had any all day.
-Thank you.
-Why did you only get one?
Oh, right.
-Do you want me to help you?
-No, it's fine.
-Come sit.
-Right.
Thank you.
Mom.
What's that for?
You're going to eat two?
It's for you.
-Enjoy your food.
Honestly, I still don't have the heart
to leave Mom here.
I think it's all right.
Let's just stay here. It's okay.
What about your work?
That's a piece of cake.
I can work on the learning material
from here too.
All I need to do is send it.
I can take care of it.
Or you can go back first.
I'll stay here with Mom for a while.
Is that what you want?
Do you want me to go back to Jakarta
or do you want me to stay here?
Stay here.
But I just feel bad
because of your work.
Okay.
So, do you want us
to go back or to stay here?
Let's just go back to Jakarta together.
Okay.
Are you sure?
I'm sure.
I just keep thinking about it because
losing Dad must be rough for Mom.
Yes.
It's definitely rough for her.
Losing someone that we love
is very rough.
Have you ever lost someone
that you love?
Not yet.
Does "not yet" mean you will?
What else haven't I packed yet?
I think you haven't packed the soap yet.
It's in the bathroom.
-Right.
-Do you want me to help you?
No, it's fine.
You guys go ahead inside the house.
I'll get the suitcase.
Inggit.
Tristan knows that you're married.
The others already know too.
-How did they know?
-Well,...
Tristan went to Yogyakarta.
I didn't know.
He said that Mr. Arya saw him too.
Mr. Arya didn't tell you?
All right.
-I'll go home now, okay?
-Thanks, Iim.
-Be careful on your way back.
-I will.
Arya.
Yes? Iim already left?
Did you know
that Tristan came to Yogyakarta?
You saw Tristan?
Arya.
You knew that Tristan came
to Yogyakarta, right?
Yes, I know Tristan came to Yogyakarta.
I saw him.
And I saw him quietly standing there.
He stood there, looking at me.
Looking at you. Looking at your mom.
-You're just telling me now?
-Not that I wanted to tell you now.
-I already knew...
-When were you going to tell me?
-I asked you and you just answered me.
-I was waiting for the right time.
When's the right time, Arya?
I asked you and you just answered me.
-Inggit, listen.
-Why didn't you tell me?
Your situation at that time
didn't allow for me to tell you...
-How did you know my situation...
-Because I could see that.
-I'm your husband, so I know.
-All you did was see.
-Did you feel what I feel?
-I know what I have to say.
-How did you know?
-And when's the right time.
-And yesterday wasn't the right time.
And if he was doing the right thing...
How did you know
it wasn't the right time?
Why didn't he meet you?
Did he came to you...
-and say he's sorry for your loss?
-That's not my question, Arya.
I'm asking why you didn't tell me.
-That's it.
-It's not I didn't want to tell you.
-So, why?
-I already said I was waiting...
Now let's sit and talk.
Sit.
-Why didn't you tell me?
-Listen.
Why didn't I tell you right away
when I saw him there?
Didn't tell you right away?
Because I thought it wasn't right.
-That's what you thought.
-Listen to me first. You were grieving.
-Yeah, but that's what you thought.
-And I would have added another burden.
How would you know that if you told me
you'd have added another burden for me?
How would you know?
-Did you ever discuss it with me?
-No, my question now is this…
-I knew that you were worried...
-When I went through all that...
He came there, he didn't meet you.
-Arya!
-Whose problem is that? Ask him.
-Don't ask me.
-Why should I ask him?
Right now, I'm asking you.
At that time,
while I was going through all that,...
did you ever asked me how I felt?
Did you ever ask me to discuss it
with you?
You never asked me!
You only say
"I know what's best for you."
-"I know what's best for you."
-I know what's best for you.
-So what's my purpose here?
-And no matter what...
I'm your husband and I'm older than you.
So, my purpose here
is just to follow what you want?
You're my husband, so I have
to always listen to what you want?
You will never ask me how I feel?
Do you even care about how I feel?
Or do you actually only care
about yourself?
I think I can decide
that I want to meet Tristan right now.
And I won't ask for your permission.
It's up to you if you want to say
"I'm your husband, Inggit".
Whatever. Because I’ve never felt
that I was treated like your wife.
So, why should I ask
for your permission?
Inggit.
-What are you doing?
-I want to discuss my grades, sir.
I don't have any time. I'm busy.
You know where the door is, right?
Why are you getting angry?
I'm just giving my opinion
that the bakwan...
starting from its texture,
isn't crunchy enough.
And it's too salty.
It's like a fake bakwan.
Then it suits you.
A fake bakwan for a fake husband.
Instead of waiting
for something unclear,...
just choose what's clear
right in front of your eyes.
I know that my feelings might
not be important to you.
You would never understand
because you don't have a heart.
You don't need to try so hard
to be a good husband to me.
You're my mom and dad's ideal
son-in-law.
You don't need to go through the trouble
of trying so hard to win my heart.
It's hard to change my mind.
Prof, good afternoon.
-Have you seen Tristan?
-I haven't seen him.
Thank you.
-Have you seen Tristan?
-Yeah?
I haven't seen him.
Dave. You're Dave, right?
-Yeah. Inggit.
-Yeah, it's Inggit.
-You can just go ahead.
-Okay. I’ll go.
Dave, do you know where Tristan is?
I called him but his phone isn't active.
Dave.
-I don't know where he is, Inggit.
-There's no way you don't know.
You're his best friend and his roommate.
How could you not know where he is?
What I know is that he's feeling
really down.
It must be because of me.
All right. Where is he?
I want to see him.
I don't know what you did to him...
to the point that he wants to move away.
Move away? What do you mean?
I don't know where he is, Inggit.
And maybe...
he doesn't want to see you again.
Good bye, Inggit.
Inggit?
Hey. Inggit, listen to me first.
Inggit.
There's something I need to tell you.
Hey, what are you doing?
You don't have to do this. Hey.
Inggit, what are you doing?
I'm going to Iim's house.
I'm going to live there for a while.
And I'm also going to look for Tristan.
Look for Tristan?
Why do you have to live...
Listen to me first. Inggit.
Come on. Don't be childish, Inggit.
We can talk about this properly.
Listen to me first.
Why? Inggit.
Stop. Listen to me first.
If someone needs to leave this house,
it should be me. Not you.
This is your house, right?
-I'll leave.
-Yes, this is my house.
But have I ever had a place here?
It's not...
Stop.
Can you listen to me?
If you leave now to see Tristan,
to look for Tristan,...
I'll think that you chose him
over our marriage.
Is that what you want?
Are you sure?
Inggit.
I'm allowed to have a choice now?
Inggit. Wait, listen to me first.
Please. Okay.
Sorry.
Wait and listen to me.
Let me take you
to where you can meet Tristan.
At least give me a chance
to make sure that you'll be okay.
I'll take you to where you can meet him.
I know where Tristan is.
I talked to Professor Gunawan.
I know where he is.
You can meet him and it's up to you
what you want to do.
I will wait for you.
But let me take you there.
Okay?
Okay, wait.
I'll get the car keys. We'll go.
I'll take you there, okay?
-Good evening, sir.
-Good evening.
-Excuse me. I want to ask something.
-Yes?
How do I get
to the Jayagiri community health clinic?
It's still far from here.
It's at the top of a hill.
The roads are steep too.
It's dangerous to go there late
at night like this.
How about you go there in the morning?
Is there a hotel near here?
There is. Over there.
-Okay. Thank you, sir.
-Yes, you're welcome.
Inggit.
The community health clinic is still far
and the road is dark.
Is it okay if we stay at a hotel
for tonight?
-It's over there, right?
-Yes, go straight and to the right.
Okay.
Arya.
Are you asleep?
I am.
-You're lying.
-Of course I'm lying.
I answered you.
What is it?
Why are you doing all this?
Coming all the away from Jakarta.
Wasting your time.
Just to take me to meet Tristan.
I know that you're doing all this
for me, but...
It doesn't make sense.
Why doesn't it make sense?
Because...
I don't think a husband
would let his wife be with another man.
You were the one...
who told me that this marriage
wasn't a real marriage.
Do you want to know my real reason?
I made a promise to your dad.
A promise that I still hold onto
to this day...
that I would put your happiness
over mine.
And I think... Yes.
Your happiness is being with Tristan.
So, by doing this, I'm only trying
to keep true to my promise.
Arya.
What is it now?
That time, you told me that you
had your reasons for marrying me.
What is it?
If you remember
your seventh birthday,...
your dad's friend...
brought his kid.
A boy.
At that time, it had only been a year
since the kid's mom left him.
And he really felt the loss.
Not long after that,
his dad was married again.
He lost his smile.
He lost his happiness.
And then that kid met you.
And that changed his life.
For the first time, Inggit.
That kid could smile again.
He found his happiness.
And then, you became my student.
So, I did not want to throw away
that chance.
No matter the risks.
I have been in love with you
since back then.
Since I met you at the campus.
But again...
your happiness is above everything else.
♪Hate is an easy thing to say♪
♪Spoken when your heart is in doubt♪
♪Doubts that arise out of fear♪
♪An unrequited love♪
♪You and I are false images♪
♪Of a successful happy relationships♪
Wait here, okay?
I want to check if Tristan is up there.
♪The further I go to leave you behind♪
♪I'm getting closer to you instead♪
-Excuse me. Is Tristan here?
-Yes, Tristan's here.
-I'll go get him.
-Sure. Thank you.
Tristan.
Inggit's here and she wants to see you.
She said she wants to talk to you.
Do you want me to wait here?
Thank you for everything, Arya.
Hi, Inggit.
Hi.
I want to explain everything.
How it ended up this way.
You have the right
to know about it directly from me.
I thought about it...
over and over again.
I thought about what I should say.
What words should come out of my mouth
when I saw you again?
A lot of different words.
A variety of sentences.
About the feeling of regret.
Sadness.
And longing.
And...
What?
And what came to me
was just one word, Inggit.
Sorry.
I'm sorry that I wasn't by your side
when you needed me the most.
You don't need to apologize to me.
Yes, I know. I should ask myself
for forgiveness, right?
Because of my behavior.
Because of what I did.
I lost the most important person
in my life.
And I didn't even know
if I would ever see her again or not.
You're sure that you lost me?
Since when?
Just a couple of minutes ago, Inggit.
When I saw the way you looked
at Mr. Arya.
Learn from my mistakes, okay, Inggit?
Don't be too late to confess your love.
Oh, my gosh.
What is it?
Hey. Inggit.
Inggit.
What is it? What's wrong? Inggit.
Hey, wait. Why are you running?
Inggit, can't you stop first
and then we talk?
Inggit. No. Stop.
-What is it?
-Arya, who am I?
Well, you're obviously
the daughter of your parents.
Is that it?
Well, you're my wife
if I'm still allowed to say that.
-Really?
-Yes.
How come I never felt like
I was treated as a wife?
-Can we not fight about that here?
-I don't want to fight about it.
I just want to tell you that I never
felt like I was treated as a wife.
You're still my lecturer.
I'm still your student.
It doesn't feel like
we're husband and wife at all.
Listen. I'll explain. Can I?
Yes, okay.
I felt that I only wanted
to guide you...
-Guide?
-To teach...
Teach? Is that a lecturer or a husband?
But I just wanted you to become better.
So, you don't believe that I can decide
what's best for myself?
You don't believe
that I can be an adult. Is that it?
It's not that I don't believe you.
-But...
Arya.
Listen. Ever since I was little,
and even until now,...
I was never given the chance
to be an adult.
All of the decisions in my life
were made by my mom and dad.
Even after we got married,...
everything at home
has to be what you want.
Even when we're fighting,...
you told me to memorize
the learning materials first.
What does the materials
have to do with learning?
Okay.
Yes.
It's my fault.
Good. That's good that you admitted it.
Say sorry first.
Don't let it be me all the time.
-I'm sorry.
-Good.
I talked to Tristan.
And I decided something
that is my choice.
Yes, okay.
And I decided...
to love Arya.
That's my choice.
I mean, I can choose now.
So, okay. My choice is to love you.
It's up to you if you want to love me...
I have one question.
-Okay.
-Okay. This is important.
-Listen.
-Stop.
Can you relax your face?
We're husband and wife.
-What did we just do? We just...
-Yeah.
-Then relax your face.
-Yeah. Okay.
From all the way there,
you were running, making me panic.
What was your reason for coming here?
Looking for network signal. Look.
I got the signal here.
-To do what?
-To...
To send this.
Let's take a photo.
Can we pose more
like a husband and wife?
No...
Do you not want to kiss me?
It's fine if you don't want to.
Okay. I'm going to send it.
To everyone.
My husband...
I'm so shy.
Cute!
I love you.
I love you too.
-Oh, my God.
-They're for real.
-So cute.
I'm so happy for her.
Look at their faces.
They look so happy.
♪Life at first feels
As beautiful as I imagined♪
♪Until you came
And disturbed this feeling♪
♪Nothing was ever wrong
There were no problems♪
♪Until you came and ruined it♪
♪I hate you♪
♪But my heart chooses love♪
♪Need to get away♪
♪Erase all traces of you♪
♪But life puts us together♪
♪You and I♪
♪Happy♪